Samantha Sanders

Front-end Developer

samantha.k.sanders@gmail.com

+64 22 317 3321

With a background in graphic design, I enjoy working closely with designers so that together we can craft beautiful and simple user experiences people will love.

I'm particularly interested in creating scalable, maintainable CSS architectures and dedicated to making experiences that are accessible and easy to use for everyone.

Key skills

- · Highly accomplished and focused on building accessible user experiences.
- Experienced at building useful and accessible React based design systems.
- Excellent at creating scalable, maintainable CSS architectures (using BEM and ITCSS methodologies).
- Passionate about building rich interactions through CSS, HTML and progressively enhanced JavaScript.
- Solid experience writing React, Typescript, ES6+ JavaScript, using Node-based tooling (Babel, module bundlers).
- Will always encourage higher levels of code test coverage, specifically with Jest and (React) Testing Library.
- Enjoy sharing my expertise with others in order to collaboratively craft and improve beautiful and usable experiences.
- Happy interacting with stakeholders/clients to provide meaningful design and technical insight in order to deliver the best experience for all users.
- Plenty of experience collaborating as part of cross-functional Agile teams.
- Comfortable conducting staff/client training and peer code reviews.
- Experience with build tools and pre-/post-processors yarn/npm, Webpack, Sass.

Employment history

Senior UI Engineer, Lendi, Sydney (Fully remote)

Apr 2022 - now

As part of the Design Systems team at Lendi, we are responsible for improving and maintaining our design system using React and Storybook. Recently we have been focussed on rebuilding components to be accessible and flexible across multiple brands for use in many varied applications.

Senior Front-end Developer, The Co-operative Bank, Wellington

Sept 2019 - Apr 2022

I worked on the newly created front-end team, helping to establish a component library as we migrated legacy apps onto newer React based platforms.

As part of the migration process I was focused on crafting usable and accessible interfaces, as well as creating high-quality, maintainable and extensible libraries and applications.

Senior Front-end Developer, Kiwi Wealth, Wellington

Feb 2019 - Sept 2019

I established the build and integration of Kiwi Wealth's component library. It consists of a React/ Typescript component library with Sass styling modules, a prototyping sandpit and documentation for how to use these new tools and processes.

An essential part of this role was to teach the team how to keep building on this future friendly foundation so that the benefits of having a consistent and resuable system could be felt by both the organisation and the end user.

Front-end Lead, Springload, Wellington

Aug 2013 - Jul 2018

I built front-end code for responsive websites and applications, helped a growing front-end team write scalable maintainable CSS, and ensured projects were built in an accessible and progressively enhanced manner. Key projects include the New Zealand Red Cross, ACC, Kiwibank, New Zealand Festival and RealMe.

Web Developer, Spark Digital, Melbourne

Aug 2012 - Jul 2013

Responsible for building responsive websites, Facebook applications, email templates, and Word-Press content management systems. As a small team it was important to be researching new technologies as the industry rapidly evolved. This helped with team collaboration to provide better end results for our clients.

Education

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Graphic Design

Canterbury University, 2007-2010

Diploma of Web Development

Natcoll Design Technology, 2011–2012